# **OWONIKOKO AYOMIDE HAKEEM**

I am a proactive, smart, driven engineer and leader with 3+ years of development experience. I have developed software solutions for business use cases from conceptualization to deployment. I am a proficient JavaScript, React developer. Software I have built includes Personal Websites, API Applications, Job Search, etc.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Gigs-Tech Solutions and Consults, Ibadan** - Frontend Developer

October 2022 - till date

- Built a community interacting website where people meets with other people with mutual interest
- Built the official website for Gigs-tech Solutions and Consults.
- Built an online event ticket where the public can book a ticket for an incoming event.
- Work well with team members for group integrations and product discussions.
- Worked with both typescript and JavaScript.

### Adeyemi Isasda Trading Company, Sagamu - Software Developer

September 2021 – September 2023

- Created an inventory website for storing and recording day-to-day transactions and store keeping.
- Implements designs for the company inventory website.
- Involved in the hiring of both backend and web designer for the company's project
- Build the company web application front-end with react, using formik for forms and error handling and tailwind and scss style framework for the implementation.
- Worked on the company's WordPress website.

### CoinCard4naira, Ibadan - Software Developer

October 2022 – October 2023

- Created an online crypto trading platform.
- Supervised the backend developer on the company's project.
- Word with other team members to achieve the company's goal.

### Budget-Flex Ltd, Ibadan - Software Developer

April 2020 – October 2021

- Part of a team of software developers that re-built the Budget-Flex website using React-Gatsby library.
- Worked on the company's user dashboard with React.js.
- Worked on the company's merchant dashboard using React.js

2, Owonikoko Street, Adexson Ile-epo Bus- stop, Lasu-Isheri Road, Lagos Nigeria. +2348155894593

Email: owonikokoayomide@gmail.com

Github:

https://github.com/owonikokomide

#### **TECHNOLOGY**

- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- Scss
- Tailwind
- JavaScript
- Typescript
- React
- Redux
- React Hooks
- Nodejs
- Express Framework
- WordPress
- MongoDB
- Firebase
- Version Control with Git and Github.

Freelance, Worldwide – Software Developer January 2020 – Till date.

#### **PROJECTS**

### **Adeyemi Isasda Trading Company:**

This is an inventory website that allows admin or staff to record and monitor their company's transaction on a daily basis.

Technologies Used: REACT, JAVASCRIPT, API INTEGRATIONS

**Link:** <u>https://isasdatc.com</u>

# **Gigs-Tech Solutions and Consults:**

This is a website that allows the pubic to create an account with Gigs-tech and to join their training either online or on site.

A mentorship, apprenticeship and internship platforms for beginners and professional

Technologies Used: REACTJS, VITE, REDUX, REACT HOOKS, SCSS

**Link:** <u>https://gigstechsolutions.com.ng</u>

### Coincard4naira:

Online gift cards and crypto trading platform that enables the users to trade their gift cards or crypto with lesser stress.

Technologies Used: HTML, SCSS, and PHP.

Link: https://github.com/owonikokomide/CoinCard4naira

# **Event Ticket (creating and booking of events):**

After creating an account on the platform, the user can now have access to create an event an generate a certain number of ticket for sales and booking.

Technologies Used: NODE, JAVASCRIPT, PRISMA, PAYSTACK, TYPESCRIPT, EXPRESS FRAMEWORK, REACT.JS, REACT HOOKS, REDUX, MYSQL.

Link: <a href="https://github.com/owonikokomide/Event-ticket">https://github.com/owonikokomide/Event-ticket</a>

## **Music Web App:**

A music uploading web app where a registered user can upload music for the public to download

Technologies Used - React.js, Redux, SCSS, JavaScript and MySQL.

**Link:** <u>https://github.com/owonikokomide/Music-Plus</u>

### **Co-operative Admin Dashboard:**

A co-operative platform that records and show the amount of users and allows the admin create and new user with a unique dashboard. Technologies Used: Web3, React.js, React Hooks, Redux, MySQL.

Link: <a href="https://github.com/owonikokomide/Thrift-By-Gigs">https://github.com/owonikokomide/Thrift-By-Gigs</a>

#### **EDUCATION**

Kwara State Polytechnic, Ilorin— National Diploma (ND) in Banking and Finance

**SEPTEMBER 2013 - JULY 2015** 

(Lower Credit).

Kwara State Polytechnic, Ilorin—Higher National Diploma (HND) in Banking and Finance

JANUARY 2018 - FEBERARY 2020

(Lower Credit)

#### **CERTIFICATION**

NYSC completed (2020)

Place of primary assignment – Arigbede College, Lokoja Kogi State

**Gigstech Solutions and Consults Programming Training** 

(February 2020)

### **REFERENCE**

# **Available on request**